♪♪～
[Tsu Terakado]
(お通)買わないと
ほくろ引きちぎるよ
♪♪『お前の父ちゃん ××』
[To All NEET Guys Throughout the Country.]
[Her long-awaited new single...]
Tsu Terakado's third single, "Your Older Brother's a Hikikomori."
[Tsu Terakado's third single:
Your Older Brother's a Hikikomori.]
We're so annoyed now, so go and do some volunteer work!
[Tsu receives a threatening letter. A mystery shadow lurks.]
[Today's "Gin Tama" is a mystery story. Who could the culprit be?!]
♪♪『お前の兄ちゃん 引きこもり』
[Shinpachi Shimura - Tsu Terakado Fan Club President]
(親衛隊)おぉ～
隊長が泣いたぞ！ すごいや!!
The President's crying! Incredible!
(軍曹)やっぱ 今回の
お通ちゃんの曲 最高でしょ？
Otsu's new song must be her greatest hit ever!
Yeah, it moves me even more than her other songs.
(新八)あぁ…
いつにも増して ｼﾞｰﾝとくるな｡
『お前の父ちゃん ××』以来の
名曲じゃないか？
Maybe it's her best since "Your Father's a Bleep Bleep"?
今度 『歌っていいとも』に
出るらしいっすよ｡
I hear she's appearing on "Utatte Iitomo."
どんどん有名になってくな
お通ちゃん｡
Otsu-chan's becoming more and more famous.
お通ちゃんが有名になるのは
嬉しいけど➡
I'm happy that Otsu-chan will become a star, but on the other hand, it's a bit sad...
なんか 反面 ちょっと寂しい…｡
(軍曹)ごふっ…！
軍曹 どうした!?
What's wrong, Sergeant?
P-President... check this out.
隊長… これを…｡
[Lead Singer of Boy Band "Hansamu"!
Goemon's Hot New Love Reveled!
Late Night Date with Idol Tsu Terakado!]
(２人)ぐはっ！
["Even Teen Idols Act Like You Guys"]
(銀時)なんだっつうの｡
What's the big deal?
ｶﾞｷの色恋なんざ
どうでもいいんだって｡
Who cares about a kid's puppy love?
それより
ﾄﾞﾗﾏの再放送は どうしたの？
[Odd Jobs - Gintoki Sakata]
More importantly, what happened to my drama rerun?
What happened in the battle between Pinko and Harue?
ﾋﾟﾝ子と春恵の対決は
どうなったの？
Just when Pinko and Harue were about to finally have their showdown,
(神楽)ﾋﾟﾝ子と春恵
いよいよ決着かと思われたとき➡
[Kagura - Odd Jobs Apprentice]
地球に 恐怖の宇宙帝王が 襲来｡
the fearsome Alien Emperor attacked Earth.
Pinko and Harue joined forces to defeat the Emperor. The end.
ﾋﾟﾝ子と春恵が 協力して
帝王 倒して 終わりよ｡
ﾏｼﾞでか!? なんで知ってんの？
Are you serious?! How do you know that?
昨日で最終回だったもんね 定春｡
Yesterday was the final episode. Right, Sadaharu?
んだよ ﾁｸｼｮｰ！ 見逃したぜ！
Oh my god!! I totally missed it!
もう ﾋﾟﾝ子に会えねえのか ｵﾚは！
You mean I'll never get to see Pinko again?
それより 新八の様子が
おかしいｱﾙよ｡
Never mind that... Shinpachi's been acting strange.
(神楽)ずっと 日めくりｶﾚﾝﾀﾞｰ
めくり続けているｱﾙね｡
He keeps tearing days off the calendar.
おい んなことしても
別の時空へは行けねえぞ｡
Hey, doing that isn't going to get you into another dimension.
現実から逃げてんじゃねえ｡
Stop running from reality.
ｱｲﾄﾞﾙなんぞに惚れるから
んなことになるの｡
This is what happens when you fall in love with an idol.
Next in the news...
分をわきまえろ｡ ｵﾚも
お天気おねえさんのﾌｧﾝだけど…｡
Know your place.
This just in! Popular weather announcer lady...
I'm a fan of the weather lady, but I know better...
(ｱﾅｳﾝｻｰ)結野ｱﾅが
結婚していたことがわかりました｡
Ketsuno was married last month.
(神楽)あらら ２人とも
別の時空へ行ってしまったｱﾙ｡
Great, now both of them have disappeared into another dimension.
(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
おっ こんな状態でも➡
Oh, even when he's zoning out, his body automatically reacts to a potential job!
体には 雑用係の習性が
染みついているね｡
は～い 新聞なら いりま… うっ！
We don't need any newspapers.
お通ちゃん!!
[Tsu Terakado - Idol]
Otsu-chan.
｢男と別れろ
さもなくば 殺すﾄﾛﾍﾞﾘｰ｣？
"Break up with the guy, or I'll kill you berry much"?
この 知性のかけらもねえ
言い回しは ｱﾝﾀのﾌｧﾝの仕業か？
Is the writer of this witless note one of your fans?
(お通)こんな手紙が
事務所に 何通も送られてくるの｡
Several letters like this have been sent to my agency.
怖くて 父ちゃんに相談したら
ｱﾝﾀなら なんとかしてくれるって｡
It freaked me out, so I told my dad. He said you'd help me.
あの親父か｡ 元気でやってんの？
That father of yours... Is he doing well?
♪♪～
(お通)うん｡ この話したら
また脱獄するって 大騒ぎしてた｡
Yes. When I told him about these death threats, he lost it-threatened to break out of prison again.
ﾌｯ そりゃ 親父が ﾊﾞｶやる前に
なんとかしなきゃな｡
We'd better do something before your father does something stupid.
それじゃあ
力になってくれるんだね？
So you'll help?!
だが 犯人の目星をつけるにしても
ｱﾝﾀのﾌｧﾝ 何人いるの？
But the problem is, the list of suspects includes all of your fans.
たぶん
業界の人のような気がする…｡
I have a feeling it's probably someone in the business...
Ever since these letters started coming in, strange things have been happening around me.
(お通)その脅迫状が
くるようになってから➡
私の周りで 変なことが
起こるようになったんだ｡
It...happens only at the TV station and on location.
それが ﾃﾚﾋﾞ局や
ﾛｹ現場ばかりで…｡
あんなこと
一般のﾌｧﾝじゃ できっこないよ｡
No ordinary fan would have access to do those things.
う～ん…｡
(神楽)別れりゃいいじゃん｡
Break up with him.
Break up with him, and everything will work out.
別れりゃ
すべて丸く収まる話じゃん｡
ｲ… ｲﾔだよ そんなの｡
考えられない｡
I-I don't want to. I can't imagine doing that.
あの人は 芸能界で 唯一
私に優しくしてくれたんだから｡
He's the only guy in show biz who's ever been nice to me!
ｹｯ 男なんて 女には みんな➡
Bah! Guys are always nice to hot girls!
優しいもんなんだよ
小娘が… ｲﾀｯ！
犯人が絞れないなら
張りついて守るだけです！
If we can't narrow down the suspects, then all we can do is stick close to you and protect you.
この 志村 新八 命に代えても
お通ちゃんを守ってみせる!!
I, Shinpachi Shimura, will protect you with my life!
あ…｡
復活した｡
He's back.
ほらほら ２人とも行きますよ！
Come on, you two! Let's get going.
The incidents aren't happening at her office.
事件は
事務所で起こってるんじゃない！
What's with that costume?
って なんですか その格好は！
耳 でかっ！ 鼻の穴 でかっ！
Huge ears! Oversized nostrils!
都知事と同じ名前の 石原です｡
My name is Ishihara, just like the Edo governor.
わかりづらいよ…｡
で 神楽ちゃんは なに？
That was difficult to tell!
And what are you supposed to be, Kagura-chan?
容疑者のｷﾞﾊﾞちゃんｱﾙ｡
Giba-chan, from "The Suspect."
つうことは お前は 交渉人だな｡
So, you must be "The Negotiator."
ｵﾚは ｻﾝﾀﾏﾘｱじゃねえ!!
I'm not Santa Maria!
おぉ あれが 彼氏？
Ohh... Is that her boyfriend?
Goemon, lead singer of the nationally popular boy band, "Hansamu"?
(神楽)国民的ｱｲﾄﾞﾙｸﾞﾙｰﾌﾟ
反侍のﾘｰﾀﾞｰ GOEMONｱﾙ｡
[GOEMON - Leader of Hansamu]
You sure know a lot. You're a big fan, aren't you?
ﾃﾒｴ やけに詳しいな｡
さては ﾌｧﾝだな？
ﾁｬﾗ男に 興味ないね｡
男は 味があってなんぼｱﾙ｡
I'm not interested in boy singers. A man's worth is determined by his "flavor."
(GOEMON)お通ちゃん…
ﾎﾞｸらが会うのは➡
Otsu-chan. I think it'd be wise to not see each other for a while, you know.
しばらく
控えたほうがいいでござる｡
What? But why, Goemon-san? I don't want to do that.
えっ… なんで？ GOEMONさん｡
ｲﾔだよ 私｡
ﾎﾞｸだって
ｷﾐと離れたくはないでござる｡
I don't want to be apart from you, either, you know.
But it isn't wise to disappoint our public too much.
でも こんなことになった以上➡
ﾌｧﾝを むやみに刺激するのは
よくないでござるよ｡
ﾌｧﾝのありがたさも 怖さも
ﾎﾞｸは ｷﾐより知っているでござる｡
I know better than you how valuable, and how frightening, fans can be, you know.
ここは しばらく時間を置こう｡
Let's give it some time.
(GOEMON)大丈夫｡
ほとぼりが冷めたら➡
Don't worry, once interest dies down in the tabloids...
また 毎日のように
会えるでござるよ｡
we'll be able to see each other every day.
(お通)GOEMONさん…｡
Goemon-san...
♪♪～
Nice, Otsu-chan. You're the best in Japan!
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)いいね お通ちゃん！
日本一！
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)じゃあ 次は
世界一 いってみようか！
Next, let's have a world's-best look!
Right!
(お通)はい！
[Otsu's Mother - Manager]
(お通の母)また あなたたち？
今度は 何の用？
You people again? What is it this time?
お通ちゃんが
脅迫されているそうで…｡
It seems Otsu-san is being threatened.
その警護 兼 事件解決を
依頼されました｡
We've been hired to guard her and solve the case.
お通 また ﾑﾀﾞなことを…｡
Otsu went and did something unnecessary again.
えっ どういう意味ですか？
What? What do you mean?
A threat letter or two happens all the time with celebrities.
脅迫状の１つや２つ
芸能界では 日常茶飯事よ｡
そんなの
いちいち 相手にしてたら➡
If we worried about every single one, we wouldn't make it in this business.
この業界では
やっていけないでしょ｡
でも あの脅迫状を➡
But weren't you the one who showed the threat letter to Otsu-chan?
お通ちゃんに見せたの
あなたなんじゃ…？
私としては
少し 立場をわきまえろ って➡
What I wanted, was for her to be a bit more conscientious of who she is.
警告の意味だったんだけど…
すべては ﾑﾀﾞだったわ｡
But I guess it was a waste.
(母)あのｽｷｬﾝﾀﾞﾙで これから
あの子は どうなることか｡
Who knows what she'll do about that scandal.
(母)ま… ｼﾞｬﾏにならない程度に
やってちょうだい｡
Anyway...
go ahead, but don't interfere with her work, please.
(神楽)どうするｱﾙ？ ﾀｶ｡
そうだな ﾕｰｼﾞ｡
What're we going to do, Taka?
Let me think about it, Yuji.
とりあえず 竜神会の
氷室と鮫島を あたろう｡
We'll start by checking out Himuro and Samejima of the Ryujinkai.
叩けば 何か➡
We should be able to shake a few skeletons out of their closets.
ﾎｺﾘが出るかもしれねえ｡
ｵｰｹｰ｡
Okay.
危ない！
Watch out!
Who's Himuro?! Who's Samejima?!
氷室って誰！ 鮫島って誰!?
♪♪～
Get home safely, guys!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)気をつけて帰れよ ﾃﾒｴら！
調査の結果 何人かの容疑者が
浮かび上がりました｡
My investigation has uncovered... Several possible suspects.
まずは ﾀﾚﾝﾄの ﾀﾓｻﾝ｡
The first, is TV personality, Tamo-san.
[Tamo-san (Multi-Talented)]
司会は もちろん
何でもこなす ﾏﾙﾁﾀﾚﾝﾄ｡
A multi-talented TV personality who can do just about anything, including, emceeing.
お通ちゃんに
ﾂﾞﾗであることをﾊﾞﾗされ➡
Otsu-chan says he wears a toupe, so he has a grudge against her.
恨みをもっているそうです｡
これが ﾑｰさん｡
広告代理店のﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｻｰ｡
This is Mu-san, an ad agency producer.
[Mu-san (Producer)]
何度か お通ちゃんに
言い寄った経験あり｡
He's approached Otsu-chan on several occasions.
ﾘｻｰﾁによると 相当なｸﾞﾗﾋﾞｱ通｡
そして➡
According to my research, he's into girlie photo mags. And then there's...
鍋尾 ｻﾑ ﾃﾞｨﾚｸﾀｰ｡
Osamu Nabe, the director.
[Osamu Nabe (Director)]
出演女優には
必ず手を出すことで➡
He's infamous in show biz for always laying his hands on the leading actresses.
業界では 有名だそうです｡
船声 英司郎 俳優
ｻｽﾍﾟﾝｽ界の第一人者｡
Eiji Funagoe, the top actor of suspense roles.
[Eiji Funagoe (Actor)]
お通ちゃんとの ｺﾗﾎﾞ企画が
あったそうですが➡
Word is there were plans for a collaboration with Otsu-chan, but it was canceled.
頓挫しています｡
Kukeko Kaki, the actress.
賀木 苦毛子 女優｡
[Kukeko Kaki (Actress)]
ふだんから お通ちゃんと
ｷｬﾗがかぶると➡
She's always complaining that her roles suffer because of Otsu-chan.
周囲にもらしていたそうです｡
主な容疑者は この５人ですかね｡
These are the five main suspects.
甘い！ 甘いぞ 新八｡
Softie. You're such a softie, Shinpachi.
え？
確かに ｿｲﾂらも➡
Certainly those people are suspects, as well.
容疑者かもしれねぇ｡
But you're forgetting the biggest suspect.
でもよ お前は
最大の容疑者を忘れてるぜ｡
最大の容疑者!?
The biggest suspect?
そうだ…
事件の陰には 必ず ﾔﾂがいる｡
That's right.
He's always in the shadows of every incident.
誰もが 犯罪の現場で
一度は目にしたことのある➡
You're forgetting the fellow who everyone has seen at the scene of a crime!
ｺｲﾂを忘れてる！
あっ それは！
謎の影！
Who is it?!
The mystery shadow.
そう… あの探偵ﾏﾝｶﾞや
その推理ﾏﾝｶﾞで出てくる➡
That's right... The mystery shadow appears in every detective or mystery manga.
謎の影！ 犯人を
明かすわけにはいかないが➡
He always appears when they don't want to reveal who the culprit is,
何をしているか
見せたいときには 必ず➡
but want to show what's happening.
出てくる あの 謎の影！
That mystery shadow.
あぁ～！ ｱﾝﾀ 誰？
Who're you?!
I am ace detective, Sleepy...
私は 名探偵 眠りの…｡
ややこしいﾏﾈすな ﾎﾞｹｰ!!
ん？
Don't go through the trouble! Stupid!
Where'd you get him from?
…つか どっから連れてきたの！
いやぁ 下のお登勢で
酔いつぶれてたんだけど➡
He was passed out drunk downstairs at Otose's. He looked the part, so I...
似てたもので つい…｡
いつか 訴えられるぞ｡
You're gonna get sued someday.
ｷｬ～!!
Cut!
(鍋尾)ｶｯﾄ～!! ｵｯｹｰ!!
Okay!
All right, Otsu-chan. Good job.
(鍋尾)はい お通ちゃん
お疲れちゃん！
お疲れさまでした～！
ありがとうございました～！
Good job, everybody. Thank you very much.
(AD)はい 次 ｼｰﾝ12のｾｯﾃィﾝｸﾞ
いきま～す!!
All right. Next let's set up scene 12.
Listen, Mu-san is supposed to be at this shoot.
いいかぁ この現場には
あの ﾑｰさんってのもいるらしい｡
気張って見張れよ！
でも さっきから➡
Keep a sharp lookout.
But I haven't seen Mu-san for a while.
そのﾑｰさんの姿が
見当たらないｱﾙよ｡
(AD)た 大変だ～！
H-Help!
The...the producer, Mu-san, is...!
(AD)ﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｻｰのﾑｰさんが！
あっ！ こ これは！
H-He's...
♪♪～
なんで 崖の先端に 露天風呂が…｡
What's an open-air spa doing at the edge of a cliff?
え～ 皆さん
この事件 どう思われますか？
Everyone, what do you make of this case?
１枚の 脅迫状から始まり➡
It began with a single threat letter, but now we have a victim.
とうとう 犠牲者が
出てしまいましたね｡
う～ん この完全犯罪
犯人は きっと➡
The perpetrator is no doubt gloating about his perfect crime.
陰で
ほくそえんでいることでしょう｡
ん～ う～ん…
めくるめく連続殺人｡
Those dazzling serial murders...
迫り来る謎の影｡ そして➡
The mystery shadow approaches...
And the trick to a murder committed in a sealed room with no exit.
脱出不可能かと思われる
密室殺人のﾄﾘｯｸ！
う～ん… ﾀﾈあかしは CMのあとで｡
The secret will be revealed after this commercial break.
どこが連続だ！
しかも 密室じゃねえ!!
What serial murders?! This isn't a sealed room!
♪♪～
どうして ﾑｰさんが…｡
(神楽)はいはい そこまでｱﾙよ！
Why was Mu-san...?
All right, we'll take it from here.
おっ!?
このﾔﾏは ｵﾚたちが預かる｡
We're taking this case. Don't touch anything unnecessary and don't destroy evidence.
余計なもんにさわって
証拠をﾀﾞﾒにすんなよ！
余計なのは お前らだよ!!
You're the ones who're unnecessary!
(神楽)ふ な…➡
Sea...
...louse...
む し｡
これは ﾀﾞｲｲﾝｸﾞﾒｯｾｰｼﾞ！
It's his dying message!
だから 捜査を
混乱させるなって!!
Stop messing up the investigation!
[TEL]
あっ！ GOEMONさん！
Goemon-san! Right now? I'm at a hot spa for a drama shoot...
えぇ 今ですか？
温泉にﾄﾞﾗﾏのﾛｹ… ﾌﾌﾌ もう！
Oh you...
(お通)GOEMONさんたら！
はい 頑張ります！
Sure, I'll do my best.
そっちは どうですか？
まぁ よかったですね！
How about you? Oh, that's great!
(謎の影)あ～…｡
What a dufus.
ﾊﾞｶなﾔﾂだなぁ！
首を突っ込めば➡
You knew you were gonna get hurt if you stuck your nose into this-you saw it coming.
ｲﾔな思いをするのは
目に見えてたろ？
おとなしく 家で ｶﾚﾝﾀﾞｰ
めくってればよかったのによ～｡
You should've behaved yourself and stayed at home-peeling the pages of your calendar.
お通ちゃんは ﾎﾞｸが守るって
言ってるでしょ｡
I told you I was going to protect Otsu-chan.
Trying to show off is a waste of time.
いいかっこ しようったって
ﾑﾀﾞだぜ｡
恋する娘は ｲﾉｼｼと同じよ！
A girl in love is like a wild boar-it only looks forward.
前しか見ちゃいねえぜ｡
そんなんじゃないですってば｡
It's not like that at all....
お通ちゃんはね
ﾎﾞｸの恩人なんですよ｡
I owe Otsu-chan my life.
It was before I met you, Gin-san.
あれは 銀さんと会う前｡
I was still working part-time jobs.
ﾎﾞｸが まだ ﾌﾘｰﾀｰをやってて
何やってもﾀﾞﾒで➡
I wasn't good at anything I did and was always getting scolded by the manager.
いつも 店長に怒られていた頃
何もかもｲﾔになって➡
I was sick of everything and I was about to throw it all away and...
全部 投げ出そうとしたことが
あったんです｡
そんなとき 聞こえてきたんです｡
That's when I heard her.
((♪♪｢あぁ だったら
はっきり言ってやる｣
♪♪｢あぁ いい加減にしないと｣))
To be honest, I didn't know what she was singing about,
正直 何歌ってるのか
よくわからなかったけど➡
お客さんも 誰もいないのに
精一杯 歌ってる姿 見てたら➡
and there wasn't an audience, but when I saw her singing her guts out...
なんか 涙が出てきて…｡
my eyes teared up.
((♪♪｢お前の母ちゃん
(ﾋﾟｰ音)だぁ！｣
(ｷﾞﾀｰ)
(拍手)
ありがとう！))
Thank you...
お通ちゃんは きっと
覚えてなんかいないだろうけど➡
Otsu-chan probably doesn't even remember me, but she made me feel a lot better that day.
ﾎﾞｸは あのとき
いっぱい 元気もらったんですよ｡
なんでもいいんです｡
できることがあるなら➡
Anything at all.
If there's anything I can do, I want to do it to pay her back for her kindness.
あのときの
恩返しがしたいんです｡
こんなことしか
ﾎﾞｸには できないけど➡
This is all I can do, but I want to help her any way I can.
何か してあげたいんです｡
そうかい… ｵﾒｴがそう言うなら
もう 何も言うめぇ｡
I get it.
If that's how you feel, then I have nothing more to say.
銀ちゃん 銀ちゃん 大変ｱﾙ！
Gin-chan, Gin-chan, big news!
うん？
ﾋﾟﾝ子がいたよ！
Pinko's here!
ﾋﾟﾝ子が 『渡る世間は
鬼しかいねぇ ｺﾉﾔﾛｰ!!』の➡
Pinko's here to tape "In This World, There are Only Demons, You Bastard!!"
収録に来てるｱﾙ！
なに～!?
What? Pinko...! I want...
ﾋﾟﾝ子～！ ｻｲﾝくれぇ～！
your autograph!
Oh...the broadcast of "Utatte Iitomo" is ending soon.
あっ もうすぐ
『歌っていいとも』の➡
放送が終わるな｡
今のうち 厠 行っとこ｡
Better use the john now.
♪♪～
[In This World, There are Only Demons, You Bastard!!]
Dad! Two dads?
(ﾋﾟﾝ子)あっ！ 父さんが２人！
(春恵)どっちが本物なの？
Which one is the real one?
How'd this happen?
(ﾋﾟﾝ子)どうして こんなことに？
(春恵)ｽｶﾞ子よ！
Sugako! This is all Sugako's fault!
みんな ｽｶﾞ子のせいなのよ！
うぅ～…｡
What good is that going to do?
あっ なんかｵﾚ
わかっちゃったかも｡
I think I know what happened.
ﾊｧ～…｡
I never imagined it would turn into a fiasco like this, you know.
(GOEMON)まさか
こんな騒ぎになるとは➡
思ってなかったでござる｡
That chick will never learn to shut her hole in front of reporters, you know!
あの女 ﾏｽｺﾐの前で 全部
しゃべりやがるでござるよ｡
《ござる？ ひょっとして これ》
"You know"? Could that be...
(GOEMON)まだ
手も 何も出してないのに➡
I haven't even groped her yet. This is ridiculous.
冗談じゃないよ… こっちは
来年 ｢大河｣も決まったし…｡
I'm signed up to do the Taiga soap next year, too.
そうそう それで こっちも
なんとかしよう思ってさ｡
That's right. So I figured I better take care of this first.
(GOEMON)やっぱ 遊びなれてない
女は ﾀﾞﾒでござるな｡
Women with no experience are no fun, after all, you know.
She fell in love with me right away just because I was nice to her, you know.
(GOEMON)ちょっと
優しくしてやっただけで➡
すぐ 本気でござるもん…｡
He's the only guy in show biz who's ever been nice to me.
((あの人は 芸能界で➡
唯一 私に
優しくしてくれたんだから…))
(GOEMON)あの女ぁ？
あれは 別にいいでござろう｡
That woman? I don't really care, you know.
She'll just disappear... anyway...
どうせ… わっはぁ～っ！
(GOEMON)ひえぇっ…
ななな… なんだお前は～!?
Wh-Wh-Who are you?!
お前… それでも人間か！
You...call yourself human?
お前の母ちゃん… ××だぁ～！
You're mother...
is a bleeping bleep!
ひえぇ～っ！
(鍋尾)おいおい
いいかげんにしてくれよ！
Hey, come on.
(鍋尾)ｽｹｼﾞｭｰﾙ
押し押しなんだからさぁ｡
Enough of this. My schedule's full.
(船声)こう見えても ｵﾚたち
忙しいんだけどなぁ｡
We may not look it, but we're very busy.
(賀木)そうよ！ 探偵だか
なんだか知らないけど➡
That's right. You might be a detective or something, but frankly, you're a nuisance.
はっきり言って迷惑なのよ！
By the way, Tama-san, why're you on the set of a drama?
ところで ﾀﾓｻﾝ
なんで ﾄﾞﾗﾏの現場にいるの？
(ﾀﾓｻﾝ)えっ？
ｵﾚは あれだよ… ｽﾄｰﾘｰﾃﾗｰ？
What? I'm, you know, the storyteller.
最初に ｼﾞｬﾏをするなって
言ってあったと思うけど｡
I told you from the beginning not to get in our way.
いやぁね… ｵﾚも➡
Well, I wanted to stay out of your way,
but I found out who the culprit is.
そうしようかと
思ってたんだけどねぇ…｡
わかっちゃったからさぁ 犯人が｡
(みんな)えぇっ!?
Let's make it quick and get it over with.
とりあえず ちゃっちゃとやって
お開きにしようや！
犯人は…！
The culprit is...
♪♪～
You!
お前だぁ！
えぇっ！
What're you talking about?!
なに言ってんだ ｱﾝﾀ！
I'd have no reason to do such a thing!
I'm the one who solves the riddles.
ｵﾚが そんなこと
するわけないでしょう！
むしろ 謎を解くほうだからさ！
ﾌﾝ… 犯人は 皆 そう言いますよ｡
That's what all criminals say.
動揺して ｲﾔな汗が出てますよ…
船声さん｡
You're panicking and starting to sweat, Funagoe-san.
そっ… そこまで言うなら
まずは証拠を見せろ 証拠を！
If you're going to accuse me, show me some proof first! Proof!
証拠？ 証拠ねぇ…｡
Proof...proof, you say...
犯人はお前だ！
その ﾎｸﾛが怪しい!!
You're the culprit!
That mole is suspicious.
I have an alibi.
私には ｱﾘﾊﾞｲがあります！
Oh, I see. Then...
あっ そうですか… じゃあ…｡
犯人は お前だ！
You're the culprit.
That's not possible.
んなわきゃない！
ｱﾝﾀ もしかして➡
Are you just saying these things because you feel like it?!
なんとなく言ってるだけ
なんじゃないの？
No, it's not really that, but...
いやっ そういうわけじゃ
ないんですけど…｡
I've seen through everything you've done!
お前のやったことは
すべて まるっとお見通しだ！
…ｱﾝﾀ 誰？
Who're you?
(神楽)ｱﾀｼかい？ ｱﾀｼは
｢ﾄﾘｯｸ｣の先生だよ！
Who am I?
I am the Sensei of criminal tricks.
お～い 10ﾁｬﾝと ４ﾁｬﾝが
混ざってんぞ～｡
Hey, you've got channel 10 and channel 4 mixed up!
犯人なら もうわかってますよ｡
I already know who the culprit is.
ｺｲﾂは…！
GOEMONｱﾙ！
That's...
Goemon.
なにこれ… どうなってんだ？
What is this? What's going on?
The second victim.
第二の犠牲者！
No. This isn't a victim.
いえ ｺｲﾂは
犠牲者なんかじゃありません｡
さっき 厠で聞きました｡
I heard him talking in the john.
This guy is a scumbag who toyed with Otsu-chan's heart.
ｺｲﾂは お通ちゃんの心を
もてあそんだ 最低の男です｡
最低の遊び人で お通ちゃんとの
ｽｷｬﾝﾀﾞﾙで 迷惑していた…｡
A scumbag playboy who considered the scandal with Otsu-chan a nuisance.
それじゃ ｺｲﾂが犯人ｱﾙか？
Then, he is the culprit?
それは…｡
(悲鳴)
Well...
こりゃぁ…｡
お通ちゃん！
That was...
Otsu-chan!
♪♪～
ｷｬｰｯ！
お前は!?
You're!
謎の影！
ﾎﾝﾄに いた！
The mystery shadow!
It really does exist. How about that? It really exists.
ﾎﾝﾄに いたよ おい！
お通！ 大丈夫!?
Otsu, are you all right?!
(お通)助けて～！
あっ UFO！
Help me!
Look! A UFO!
After him, Shinpachi!
追うぞ 新八！
はいっ！
Right!
♪♪～
(AD)うわぁっ！
待て～！
Stop!
♪♪～
This is fine work...
(中嶋)いやぁ いい仕事…｡
(中嶋)お… お宝 お宝が～！
The treasure... The treasure!
(結野ｱﾅ)明日も引き続き…
うわっ！
Tomorrow, we will continue to see...
Commercial! Cut to commercial!
(ﾃﾞｨﾚｸﾀｰ)CMだ！ CMいけ!!
♪♪～
Give it up already!
いいかげんに… 観念しやがれ！
He missed me...
ﾍｯ どこ投げてやがんだ！
だぁっ… うわぁ～っ！
Hey, you! Show your true self!
おい お前！
とっとと正体 現すｱﾙよ！
いえ… 私 生まれつき
この姿の天人なんですけど…｡
No, I've been like this from birth. I'm an Amanto.
えっ どういうこと？
Huh? What do you mean?
Uh...I'm at a loss to explain.
いえ… どういうことと
言われても 困るんですけど➡
My form doesn't change when light shines on me.
ﾗｲﾄが当たったからって➡
この姿が変わるわけじゃ
ないってことでしょうか｡
あ～っ！
私 この人 見たことある！
I know you! I've seen him before.
Everywhere I went there was always somebody who looked like him.
私の行く先々で
なんか こんなの いつもいた！
いえいえ！ 別に
怪しい者じゃないんですよ｡
I'm not anyone suspicious.
私は ただ お通ちゃんのﾌｧﾝで…➡
I'm just a fan of Otsu-chan.
ｻｲﾝをもらおうと この数週間
狙ってただけで…｡
I've been after her for several weeks in order to get her autograph.
それは つまり ｽﾄｰｶｰじゃねえか！
In other words, a stalker.
You're complicating things, idiot!
紛らわしいんだよ このﾎﾞｹ！
H-Help me!
You must be the culprit!
お前が 犯人なんだな！
You messed up her dressing room and sent that death threat letter!
楽屋を荒らしたのも
脅迫状を送ったのも！
なんのことですか！
What're you talking about?!
I did rifle through her dressing room,
but I never sent any letter.
楽屋は 確かに荒らしましたけど
私は 脅迫状なんて…！
Then who sent the death threat letter?
それじゃあ…
脅迫状を送ったのは…｡
結果的に お通ちゃんと
あの男が別れて➡
Who would benefit from Otsu-chan and that guy breaking up?
誰が得をするのか…｡
結論を言えば それは
お通ちゃん本人…｡
Hmm, that would be Otsu-chan herself.
The letter was sent by whoever wishes the most for Otsu-chan's happiness.
脅迫状は お通ちゃんの幸せを➡
いちばんに願っている人物が
送りつけた…｡
それは…｡
That would be...
あなただ！
you.
えぇ… そのとおりよ｡
Yes...that's right.
お母ちゃんが…｡
You, Mo...?
I told you: I just wanted to give her a warning.
(母)言ったでしょう
私は ただ警告をしたかったって｡
Just as you people said, that Goemon is the lowest form of scumbag.
あなたたちの言うとおり
あの GOEMONとかいう男は➡
最低の男… あの子 私と似て
男運がないくせに 頑固だから｡
Like me, that girl has no luck with men, and she's stubborn to boot.
There isn't a parent around who doesn't think of their child.
子供のことを
考えない親なんて いない…｡
でも 親の気持を
わかる子供も少ない…｡
But there are also few children who understand their parents' feelings.
そんなの常識でしょ？
That's common sense.
今度は もっと 普通のやり方で
伝えてあげてください｡
Next time, convey your feelings in a more normal fashion.
不器用なのよ あの子も 私も…｡
We're both rather clumsy.
Who are you?!
…つか 誰？
(鈴の音)
I see. I understand...
そっか… わかった｡
お通ちゃん あの…｡
Otsu-chan, I...
あっ いいよ いいよ 大丈夫！
Forget it. Forget it. I'll be fine-I'm used to it.
私 慣れてるから こういうの…｡
男運 悪いの…
前に好きだった人も➡
I have bad luck with men.
The person I fell in love with before was Hard Gay.
実は ﾊｰﾄﾞｹﾞｲだったし…｡
ﾊｰﾄﾞｹﾞｲだったの!?
Hard Gay?!
お母ちゃんが せっかく
心配してくれてたのに…｡
My mother was worried about me, but I was a fool.
それなのに ﾊﾞｶみたいね…｡
Men dump me, and I've lost popularity as a pop star.
男には ふられるし➡
ｱｲﾄﾞﾙとしての人気も
下がっちゃったし…｡
I've...lost everything.
私… 何もなくなっちゃった…｡
お通ちゃん ﾎﾞｸ…｡
Otsu-chan, I...
(親衛隊たち)隊長～っ！
President!!
We came to help out.
(親衛隊)加勢にきましたぜ！
It's not fair that you're hogging all the glory!
(親衛隊)一人だけ
かっこつけるなんて➡
ずるいっすよ！
ﾎﾞｸら 徹夜で張り込みますよ！
We're prepared to stand guard all night long.
みんな…｡
All of you!
悪いけど ﾎﾞｸたち
みんな しつこいﾔﾂばかりでね｡
I'm afraid we're all very tenacious fanboys.
But we're not going to stop idolizing you over a little scandal or two!
ちょっとやそっとのｽｷｬﾝﾀﾞﾙじゃ
ｷﾐのﾌｧﾝは やめないよ！
♪♪～
(お通)ありがとう 新二君…｡
Thank you, Shinji-kun.
いや 新八なんですけど…｡
It's Shinpachi.
Oh, I just passed out in the hot spa.
This has been Ginzaburo Yakihata.
(ﾑｰさん)あの ﾎﾞｸ…
湯あたりしただけなんですけど｡
焼畑 銀三郎でした｡
[Preview]
Gin-san has amnesia?!
You mean he's forgotten me?
Don't give me that!
You mean, I remember him, but he forgot me?! That sucks!
Who does he think he is?!
The next episode: "You Always Remember the Things that Matter the Least."
[Shinpachi and Kagura do everything they can to help Gintoki remember.]
[Will Gintoki's memory return? If it doesn't...]
Not too many extras lately, huh?
Yeah.
そういえば 最近 おまけとか
ついてないですね｡
んぁ…｡